A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Commerce and Trade, 2014-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Secretary of Commerce and Trade, 2014-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)
The Library of Virginia
52175
4.70 cu. ft. (6 Boxes)
Virginia. Office of the Secretary of Commerce and Trade
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Restricted documents have been sealed within the collection by processing archivist.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 11 January 2018 by the Office of Governor Terry McAuliffe, Secretary of Commerce and Trade, 1111 East Broad Street, 4th Floor, Richmond, Virginia, 23219.
Historical Information
The office of the Secretary of Commerce and Resources was established in 1972 and was responsible for the areas of economic development and natural resources. In 1986 this secretariat was dissolved and split into two separate offices, the Secretary of Economic Development and the Secretary of Natural Resources. The name of the office was changed in 1993 from the Secretary of Economic Development to the Secretary of Commerce and Trade. Appointed by the governor as a member of their cabinet, the Secretariat's chief responsibility is to manage the direction of several state agencies concerned with the development of commerce and economic development throughout the Commonwealth. Maurice Jones served as Secretary of Commerce and Trade from 2014 through 2016, and Todd Haymore from 2016 through 2018 during Governor Terry McAuliffe's administration (2014-2018).
Some of the agencies reporting to the Secretary of Commerce and Trade include: The Board of Accountancy; The Department of Small Business and Supplier Diversity; The Department of Housing and Community Development; The Department of Labor and Industry; The Department of Mines, Minerals, and Energy; The Department of Professional and Occupational Regulation; The Tobacco Indemnification and Community Revitalization Commission; The Virginia Economic Development Partnership; The Virginia Employment Commission; The Virginia Housing Development Authority; The Virginia Resources Authority; and The Virginia Tourism Corporation.
See: Governor Terry McAuliffe Administration Web Archive Collection, 2014-2018 for more on the administration, and the Secretary of Commerce and Trade page specifically for more on the Secretariat and Assigned Agencies.
Scope and Content
The collection is housed in 6 boxes and includes agendas, meeting briefings, brochures, calendars, clippings, correspondence, itineraries, notes, programs, publications, reports, and other documents that chronicle the work of the secretariat, agency heads, and the governor related to Virginia's commerce and trade during the McAuliffe administration.
Material concerning the state's Economic Development and Tourism efforts, and the Public Relation Series (V) make up the bulk of this collection. The former documents the secratariat's involvement with economic development and tourism projects, initiatives, and events, such as international trade missions and rural infrastructure projects. Th Public Relations series is comprised mostly of meeting briefs leading up to public relation events, marketing trips, and tourism initiatives documented in the other series.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into six series:
Series I: Correspondence: Assigned State Agencies, 2014-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)
Series II: Correspondence and Subject Files: Secretariat, 2014-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)
Series III: Economic Development and Tourism, 2014-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)
Series IV: Planning and Budget, 2014-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)
Series V: Public Relations, 2016-2018
Series VI: Special Projects and Studies, 2014-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence: Assigned State Agencies, 2014-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)., Extent: 9 folders (Box 1)
  This series is housed in one box and arranged alphabetically by folder title (typically the name of a specific agency). This series also includes non correspondence material such as 2016 Labor Market Information Community Profiles from the Virginia Employment Commission. Some of the agency directors and commissioners during the McAuliffe Administration include: Jay W. DeBoer - Department of Professional and Occupational Regulation (DPOR); Ellen Marie Hess - Virginia Employment Commission (VEC); William P. Burge and C. Ray Davenport - Labor and Industry; Rita McCLenny - Virginia Tourism Corporation (VTC).
  - Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ), 2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Department of Professional and Occupational Regulation (DPOR), 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Department of Professional and Occupational Regulation (DPOR) - Complaints, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Labor and Industry, 2014-2016 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Employment Commission(VEC), 2016 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Labor Market Information Community Profile - Bristol, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Labor Market Information Community Profile - Buchanan County, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Labor Market Information Community Profile - Dickinson County, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Labor Market Information Community Profile - Lee County, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Labor Market Information Community Profile - Russell County, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Labor Market Information Community Profile - Scott County, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Labor Market Information Community Profile - Washington County, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Labor Market Information Community Profile - Wise County, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Labor Market Information Community Profile - Southwestern Virginia, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Labor Market Information Community Profile - New River/Mt. Rogers, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Labor Market Information Community Profile - State, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Weekly Meeting: January 28, 2016 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Weekly Meeting: January 28, 2016 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership: Camp Pendleton, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership: Craft Beer, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership: Virginia International Trade Corporation (VITC), 2016 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership: Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC) (1 of 2), 2016 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership: Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC) (2 of 2), 2016 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership: Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC) (2 of 2), 2016 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership: Project Cavalier, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership: Rural Relationships, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership: Tobacco, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Virginia Resources Authority, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Virginia Tourism Corporation (VTC), 2016 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Series II: Correspondence and Subject Files: Secretariat, 2014-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)., Extent: 20 folders (Box 1)
  This series in 1 box and is arranged alphabetically by folder title. Includes incoming and outgoing correspondence of Secretaries Jones and Haymore, and from Governor McAuliffe.
  - Budget, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Call Sheets, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Colorado Cycling Partnership, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Flory Small Business Center (1 of 2), 2015 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Flory Small Business Center (2 of 2), 2015 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - HB 2108-Broadband, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Rural Development, 20167 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - SB 748-Natural Gas, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - SB 1331-Natural Gas, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - SB 1349-Utility Earnings, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Solar-Legislation, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - State and Federal Mandates on Local Governments (1 of 2), 2016 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - State and Federal Mandates on Local Governments (2 of 2), 2016 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - The Catalyst (Bioscience Health Research), 2016 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Trade Missions, 2016-2017 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Transportation Partnership Opportunity Fund (TPOF) (1 of 2), 2015 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Transportation Partnership Opportunity Fund (TPOF) (2 of 2), 2015 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Utility Bills, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Virginia Energy, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership(VEDP)-Legislation, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Series III: Economic Development and Tourism, 2014-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)., Extent: 1 cu. ft. (2 boxes) (Box 1-2)
  This series is housed in 2 boxes and is arranged alphabetically by folder title. The series documents the Secretary's involvement with economic development and tourism projects, initiatives, and events, as well as interactions with outside economic development and tourism businesses, organizations, boards, and commissions. This series may include, but is not limited to: correspondence, fast facts, itineraries, briefings, and reports. A large portion of this series includes various marketing and trade mission trips to countries such as Cuba, Mexico, South Africa, and throughout Asia. Other topics include rural economic and energy development.
  - Asia Marketing Mission, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Bristol, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - California Marketing Mission, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Canada Tourism and Marketing Mission, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - China and UK Marketing Mission, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Cuba Trade Mission, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Europe Marketing Mission, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Hannover Marketing Mission, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - New York City and Dallas Marketing Mission, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Pacific Rim Marketing Mission, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Paris Air Show/Europe - Dublin, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Paris Air Show/Europe - Geneva, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Paris Air Show/Europe - Germany, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Paris Air Show/Europe - Netherlands, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Paris Air Show/Europe - Paris, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Paris Air Show/Europe - UK, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Paris Air Show/Europe - Vienna, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Richmond Exports Initiative, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Rural Power, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - South Africa (RSA) Marketing Mission, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - San Francisco/Los Angeles Marketing Mission, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Southern Virginia, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Southwestern Virginia (1 of 2), 2014 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Southwestern Virginia (2 of 2), 2014 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - State Tourism Plan (DRIVE) (1 of 2), 2013 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - State Tourism Plan (DRIVE) (2 of 2), 2013 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - TURN (Television Production), 2015 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Biosciences Health Research Corporation (VBHRC), 2017 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Employment Commission (VEC) - Overview, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership (VEDP)-Board of Directors Meeting, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership (VEDP)-Coal Trade Missions, 2015-2016 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership (VEDP)-Operational Plan Executive Summary (1 of 2), 2017-2018 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership (VEDP)-Operational Plan Executive Summary (2 of 2), 2017-2018 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership (VEDP)-Strategic Plan FY 19-23 (1 of 3), 2017 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership (VEDP)-Strategic Plan FY 19-23 (2 of 3), 2017 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership (VEDP)-Strategic Plan FY 19-23 (3 of 3), 2017 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Virginia Economic Development Partnership (VEDP)-Transitional Marketing Plan, 2017-2018 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Virginia International Trade Alliance (VITAL), 2015 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Virginia Tourism Corporation (VTC) - Transition (1 of 2), 2014 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Virginia Tourism Corporation (VTC) - Transition (2 of 2), 2014 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Whyte County, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - YES - Virginia Marketing Presentation, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Series IV: Planning and Budget, 2014-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)., Extent: 4 folders (Box 2)
  This series is housed in one box and arranged alphabetically by folder title. This series documents the interactions between the Secretary and the Governor's staff, assigned state agencies, and the Department of Planning and Budget regarding the development and modification of the Commonwealth's budget.
  - 2017-2018 Budget, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Budget Reduction Proposals, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Budget Reduction Proposals, 2018 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - House and Senate Amendments, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Series V: Public Relations, 2016-2018., Extent: 3 cu. ft. (3 boxes) (Box 2-4)
  This series is housed in one box and arranged chronologically. This series includes correspondence, event briefings, memos, brochures, but primarily meeting briefs related to public facing and relation initiatives, as well as those found in other series (i.e. foreign marketing and trade missions).
  2016
  - Sept. 1-9 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Sept. 9-15 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Sept. 15-26 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Sept. 26-30, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Oct. 1-6 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Oct. 11-12 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Oct. 12-13 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Oct. 14-20 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Oct. 20-31 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Nov. 1-9 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Nov. 9-29 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Nov. 29-30 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dec. 1-2 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dec. 1-2 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dec. 5-6 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dec. 6-9 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dec. 9-31 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    2017
  - Jan. 1-3 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Jan. 4-6 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Jan. 12-19, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Jan. 19-20, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Jan. 23-29, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Jan. 29-31, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Feb. 1-2, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Feb. 3-6, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Feb. 6-7, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Feb. 7-8, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Feb. 9-10, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Feb. 15-18, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Feb. 20-28, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - March 2-3, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - March 4-7, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - March 8-10, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - March 14-22, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - March 22-23, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - March 24, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - March 27-29, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Apr. 4-6, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Apr. 7, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Apr. 8-13, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Apr. 14-19, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Apr. 27-28, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - May 1-5, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - May 8-13, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - May 15-18, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - May 19-20, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - May 20-28, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - May 30, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - June 1-2, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - June 5-6, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - June 7-12, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - June 14-16, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - July 7-10, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - July 11-26, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Aug. 2-10, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Aug. 14-15, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Aug. 16-17, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Aug. 21-23, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Aug. 28-30, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Aug. 31, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Sept. 1-6, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Sept. 7-8, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Sept. 9, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Sept. 11-18, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Sept. 18-20, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Sept. 20-25, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Sept. 25-28, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Oct. 5-10, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Oct. 23-31, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Nov. 2-30, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Dec. 5-13, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Jan. 8-10, 2018 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Series VI: Special Projects and Studies, 2014-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)., Extent: 1 cu. ft. (3 boxes) (Box 4-6)
  This series is housed in one box and arranged alphabetically by folder title. This series documents the Secretariat's interaction with and oversight of projects and studies related to the Governor's initiatives, as well as other projects not identified in this or any other series. This includes, but not limited to: notes, briefs, reports, and correspondence.
  - Broadband, 2015-2017 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Cape Charles, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Confirmation Hearings Prep, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Early Childhood, 2014-2017 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Film Incentives, 2017 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Food Deserts, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Fort Monroe, 2016 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Higher Education, 2012-2014 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation 2019 Anniversary, 2016 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Legacy Project (1 of 2), 2017 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Legacy Project (2 of 2), 2017 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Power Purchase Agreements, 2015-2017 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Rural Prosperity, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Russell County, 2014-2015 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Small Business Investment Companies (SBIC), 2014 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Small Animal Clinical Skills Center (1 of 2), 2015 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Small Animal Clinical Skills Center (2 of 2), 2015 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Small Women and Minority Owned Businesses (SWAM) (1 of 2), 2014 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Small Women and Minority Owned Businesses (SWAM) (2 of 2), 2014 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Tobacco Commission, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Tobacco Commission, 2015 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Transition Manuals (1 of 4), 2014 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Transition Manuals (2 of 4), 2014 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Transition Manuals (3 of 4), 2014 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Transition Manuals (4 of 4), 2014 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Washington D.C. South (Carmel Church Station), 2016 (Box 6, Folder 7)